Preliminary Inventory to the Philip Zelikow and Condoleezza Rice Papers, 1989-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
Philip Zelikow and Condoleezza Rice Papers,
1989-1995
95062
Zelikow, Philip, 1954-
Rice, Condoleeza, 1954-
11 manuscript boxes 4.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, notes, speeches and writings, press releases, printed matter, and photographs, relating to the unification of Germany, and to American and Soviet foreign policy regarding it. Includes photocopies of Soviet archival documents. Used as research material forthe book by P. Zelikow and Condoleezza Rice, Germany Unified and Europe Transformed: A Study in Statecraft (Cambridge, Mass., 1995)
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1995.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Germany--History--Unification, 1990.; Germany--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Germany.; Germany--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--Germany.; Germany.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); United States--Foreign relations.
Container List
- Unpublished writings, letters, notes, memoranda, and speeches (Box 1.)
- Bibliographies (Box 2.)
- Biographical data
- Chronologies
- Photographs
- Photocopies of Russian archival documents, with translations (Box 3.)
- White House and State Department press releases, briefings, remarks, and testimony (publicly released documents) (Box 4.)
  - 1989 January-December
  - 1990 January-March (Box 5.)
  - 1990 March-May (Box 6.)
  - 1990 May-June (Box 7.)
  - 1990 July-October (Box 8.)
  - 1990 November-1991 April (Box 9.)
- Journal articles and other printed matter (Box 10-11.)